how do you make a tiny human brain grown
from stem cells conscious turns out
there's an answer now we do know that if
we pop them in computer chips and grow
them for as long as 10 months or
potentially 14 yeah the guys who are
selling them as a subscription model for
computation actually kept them alive for
56 weeks when disembodied and I mean
that quite literally they only ever
experienced Delta brain wave they're
essentially not awake nor asleep they
don't really have multiple states to
cycle through a brain stem is what
allows you to have circadian rhythm and
I assume at least some of you guys have
healthy circadian rhythm I don't This
research group implanted them into the
skulls and inside of the brains of mice
with induced microsopy that's a
condition that we see in humans where
the brain and the skull are smaller than
they should be and it results in extreme
cognitive deficits people do frequently
ask why do they work with human brains
the answer is that there's just the most
research behind the human varieties and
any data that they get out of their
research is then applicable to medicine
they also used low intensity ultrasound
to help get the cells integrated and
start functioning what they found was
incredible look at that green in the
picture there the green is going to be
the brain organoid and everything else
you see are the projections from it it's
taken over so much of the function of
the mouse's brain when embodied in a
mouse or little human brain friends gain
every brain wave they would need for fun
function this would meet the clinical
definition of Consciousness which is
being not unconscious I do keep telling
you guys when someone says the word
Consciousness they might mean different
things the psychological term is a sense
of self and that is a much higher bar
and while fish do perceive themselves in
mirrors my best guess is that every
animal has some degree of Consciousness
but what does this mean we may have a
very viable treatment for brain damage
people with traumatic brain injuries we
could take cells from you make you your
own brain organoid and integrate them
into your brain it also means that we
could potentially for the first time
ever have a treatment or things like
microso children born without major
regions of their brain we could help
them recover and live relatively normal
lives look at this Mouse's brain that is
functional integration of human cells
how freaking cool is that